45亿年前在行星形成的竞争中
4.5 billion years ago, in the high performance race to become a planet,
这个蓝色的天体成功诞生胜利地存在于宇宙中
this glistening blue sphere made it to the winners circle.
但是过程是混乱无序的
But the competition was filled with chaos
很多剧烈的碰撞
and violent collisions.
成型过程中大量的岩石
When the Earth was forming, rocks and boulders
就像汽车相撞那样高速落到地球上
came screaming in much faster than cars crash when they run into walls or other cars.
经过这样漫长的岁月
After tremendous perseverance
才在太阳系中形成如此独一无二的地方
it became a special place in the Solar System
拥有海洋 陆地和生命
to sustain oceans, land and life.
早期的细菌制造了大量氧气
The bacteria helped to create oxygen.
得益于这些低等生物才有了我们
We owe our heritage to the scum of the earth.
尽管现在还有各种灾难袭击着地球
Despite modern disasters that now plague the planet,
地球依然是宇宙中最神奇的一块乐土
it still remains one of the most mystifying creations in the Universe.
最后 登上神奇太空船--地球
Blast off aboard"Spaceship Earth".
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://www.hdcmct.com
历史频道·宇宙第一季第6集 太空船地球
影片压制:暮云春树  字幕来源：射手网 调校：TIAN@CMCT 招募Q号: 76846146
假设外星人真的存在
Suppose extraterrestrials truly exist
他们将要访问地球
and want to tour Planet Earth,
像我们最期待的那种星际旅行
they'd be in for the ultimate cosmic vacation.
地球的名称来源于希腊语
Earth, whose name may go back to the Greek name"eraze" *,
意为土地 是太阳系的第三颗行星
meaning"ground", is the third terrestrial planet from the Sun.
但当外星人到来时 他们会意识到地球的昵称--蓝色星球
But when arriving, visitors will realize that it got its nickname,"the blue planet",
因为地球表面四分之三都是水
because three quarters of it is covered with water.
这些来访者将发现
And vacationers will see
地球是太阳系中唯一的
that Earth is the only planet in our solar system
生存着人类和其他高等生物的星球
where humans, or thence life, exists.
如果他们能在地球大气中或水下呼吸
If you can breathe our oxygen-rich atmosphere, or breathe under water,
他们就可以自由探索地球而无需空间飞行器或宇航服
Earth can be explored without a protective spacecraft and space suit.
但是他们得调整他们的表
But tourists will need to adjust their watches.
地球绕太阳一圈是365天
It takes 365 days for Earth to orbit around the Sun,
每天是24小时
and each day is 24 hours,
这是地球绕地轴旋转一圈所需要的时间
which is the amount of time it takes the planet to rotate around its axis once.
尽管他们可能遇到飓风和人类战争
Despite travellers warnings about deadly storms and civil wars,
地球仍是一个相对安全的目的地
Earth is a relatively safe adventure destination.
这是个非常特别的星球
The Earth is a very special planet.
就像一辆保时捷
Just like a Porsche
是一辆特别的跑车
is a very special car.
诞生在太阳系合适的位置上
Our planet was formed in just the right place in the Solar System.
事实上太阳系中只有这个位置
In fact it's the only place we know of in our entire Solar System
适合动植物的生存
where plants and animals can live under natural conditions.
唐纳德·布朗李
Renowned astronomer Donald Brownlee,
开始进行他的宇宙赛车之旅
has spent his career on a cosmic quest
以解开原始地球之谜
to solve the mysteries surrounding the origin of Earth.
在这场成为适合生命繁衍的星球的竞赛中
He says, in the race to become a life-sustaining planet,
假设地球就是司机
Earth was in the driver's seat.
这场竞赛危机四伏
But he cautions the ride was full of danger and intrigue.
地球面临许多事件
The Earth had many things that happened to it
一切即将开始
to make it the way it is right now.
这些事件很多都伴随着幸运
And many of these things did involve luck.
45亿年前的宇宙某处
4.5 billion years ago, one corner of the Universe
经历了一场巨大的爆发
experienced a colossal fireworks display.
非常强大但短暂的大爆炸超新星爆炸
A massive but short-lived star exploded as a supernova.
爆炸物在万有引力作用下坍塌
The blast from this star may have triggered the gravitational collapse
中央形成了太阳
of the cloud that formed the Sun.
很快地
Shortly after the Sun formed, you had
周围物质开始围绕太阳旋转
a lot of material orbiting around the Sun.
这些微小的冰粒 尘土
And this was microscopic stuff, ice particles, dust,
像干燥器上的棉绒
a lot of it wasn't unlike the lint that comes out of your dryer.
刚开始时集中成一小团
And it began to kind of stick together in little clumps.
然后其中一些变得像沙石
And eventually some of these pieces became more like sand,
大多是小块的硅酸盐石头 它们又不断地
little pieces of silicate mostly, and it began to stick together
融合其他小石块
and you begin to get little rocks, little boulders.
不断的碰撞形成大石块
As the boulders grew larger, so did the collisions.
两个石块撞击后 引力使之结合
As two objects impacted, gravity held them together.
保时捷跑车以极速闻名
Porsches are known  for speed.
这些小行星也如此
Planets are also known for speed.
地球形成时期 这些微粒 石块
When the Earth was forming, particles and rocks and boulders
通常以更快的速度 远快于保时捷跑车的速度
came screaming in much faster than these cars
就像发生车祸一样碰撞在一起
crash when they run into walls or other cars.
最初的地球形成于这些碰撞
Through multiple collisions, infant Earth was formed.
要形成现在这么大的地球 还需要更多的碰撞
But it would take many more impacts for it to become the size it is today.
为了更好的理解地球形成的过程
To better understand the formation process,
皮特·舒尔茨 教授与他前任的学生 小泽杉田
Pete Schultz and his former student Seiji Sugita,
在位于美国宇航局埃姆斯研究中心的垂直射击靶场 重现了
are attempting to recreate the early impacts on Earth
地球上这些最初的碰撞
by using the Vertical Gun Range at NASA's Ames Research Centre.
塞满整个大房间的是一个巨大的轻质气体炮
It's a warehouse-sized room housing a massive light gas gun
更像洲际弹道导弹
which looks more like a ballistic missile.
这个纵向的发射器指向的特别目标
The vertical gun launches projectiles at specified targets
是一个真空室
inside a vacuum chamber.
发射器可以调整到需要的角度
The fact that this gun can load up in a different angle
可以使这个系统非常的相似于
makes it really realistic in terms of comparison
地球表面所发生的那些
to what happened on the surface of Earth
大约35亿年前的情况
about 3.5 billion years ago.
发射这样的小铝珠
So were going to fire this tiny quarter-inch aluminium sphere
到真空室之中 而我们使用这个是因为
into the chamber, and we use this because
它有着与进入地球大气的小行星几乎相同的密度 事实上
it has about the same density as an asteroid entering the atmosphere of the Earth,
冲击的速度高达3英里每秒
so it's gonna slam in around 3 miles/s.
是普通枪子弹速度的10倍
About 10 times the speed of a bullet.
发射器将铝珠打入真空室
It's gonna be smashed to smithereens. The vertical gun will shoot the aluminium bead into the vacuum chamber
里面将充满地球早期大气
filled with atmospheric gases.
现在用一堆沙子模拟
There it will impact a sandy mound
早期地球相似的地表
resembling early Earth's surface.
我们的这个空间 除了稀薄大气
We're in a vacuum chamber but we'll be putting back in a gas
模拟一个可能的早期地球环境
that will simulate what the early Earth must have looked like.
弄一些坑
Let's go ahead and make a bunch of craters,
大概像这样的早期地形
what the early landscape of Earth must have looked like.
碰撞一直存在 会有相当多的坑
Cause these things would happen all the time, there had to have been a lot of craters.
我们的碰撞计划 将击中这个表面的中央
The plan is to come in, hit the centre of the target
看看这些坑洼的表面会产生多大的破坏
and watch the crater form. And you'll see the destructive power
虽然这是一个很小的物体
of… even tough it's a tiny bead,
也能产生足够的破坏
it's gonna do some real serious damage.
没什么可以幸免
Can you believe anything would survive…
高速摄像机记录着撞击过程
High-speed cameras will document the impact.
他们从监视器上观察着
Schultz and Sugita, nervously watch the monitor
在发射器之外
located outside the gun range.
这个部分最激动人
This is the part that kills me.
就像暴风雨前夕
It's like this moment before the storm.
工程师在控制室操作着
From a secure control room, an engineer flips several switches.
好的 就要开始了
Ok. Here we go.
科学家们开始祈祷
Schultz and Sugita mix science with a little superstition.
交叉手指
We cross our fingers…
腿
Cross our legs…
手臂
Cross our hands…
太让人疯狂了
This is what drives me nuts.
漂亮
Oh, gorgeous! Oh, my gosh!
好了 让我们看看
Ok, let's take a look.
试验情况如何
The experiment worked.
难以置信
That is unbelievably…
是否想起地球上的
If we imagine this on the Earth…
嗯？
Yeah?
那些云的变化
These would be clouds that would be rolling
跟龙卷风刮起的比较
at velocities that'd be comparable to tornados.
更高 甚至更强大
- Or even higher. - Even higher, yeah.
录像显示出真实而恐怖的场景
The video taken reveals a frightening and realistic picture
正是早期地球上所发生的
of what happened on early Earth.
确实非常可怕
That's a brilliant lake!
来看看
let's go!
喔 天啊
Oh, man! Geez!
喔 实在是太梦幻了
That is absolutely gorgeous!
造成如此大的破坏
That did some serious damage.
想象一下地球上的这些小行星撞击
Just imagine that this is the asteroid that slammed in to the Earth.
不断重复地发生
This must have been happening just repeatedly,
在地球表面造成严重的破坏
doing real damage to the planet Earth.
这只是一个小实验
And it's just a small scale example
发生在早期地球的情况
of what must have happened at the early Earth.
真棒
Yes!
一些撞击地球的星体
Some of the objects blasting into infant Earth
直径超过300英里
were over 300 miles in diameter.
这种高强度撞击产生了超高温
The force of one such high velocity impact created tremendous heat.
地球内部开始变热
Earth began roasting from the inside.
铁和镍融化 汇集到地核
Iron and nickel melted and sank to the core
产生巨大热量就像炼钢炉
generating heat like a massive furnace.
岩石与融化液态的岩浆不停转换
The outer rock, or magma, was completely melted
又产生大量的岩浆灰
producing a molten ocean.
地球是飘浮在宇宙中的狂热地狱
The planet was a raging inferno floating in space,
完全的人间炼狱
literally… hell on Earth.
各种撞击更强烈地袭击地球
The most severe impacts* could've sterilized the planet.
地球表面只有蒸汽
You've got a steam atmosphere and heat on the entire surface of the Earth
并且这样的高温 跟消毒柜一样
above sterilization temperatures.
地核的形成通常称之为铁核对流
Formation of the Earth's core, sometimes called the great iron catastrophe,
在地球诞生的最初4千万年
occurred within the first 40 million years of our planet's existence,
并对我们的未来产生了深远的影响
and it had a profound effect on our future.
得益于地球的铁质核心
Within the iron core,
不断旋转对流逐渐产生了地磁场
the rotating ball of molten iron generated a remarkable magnetic field.
是地球适合生存的必须条件
This set up the conditions for a habitable planet.
地心铁的聚集
By getting all the iron down to the centre of the planet
产生固态内核 最终
you had a solid core that eventually drove
地磁场像盾一样环绕着地球
the protective magnetic field that surrounds our planet.
如果没有地磁场
Without the magnetic field
地球将没有空气 无法生存
Earth would be an airless waste devoid of life.
太阳粒子风以每小时100英里的速度来到地球
A gusty wind of materials speeds from the Sun past Earth at a million miles an hour,
把大气不断的吹离 直到完全消失
and could erode our atmosphere to nearly nothing
也只需几十万年
in a few million years.
但是地磁场保护着地球抵御太阳风
But Earth's magnetic field deflects the solar wind
保住了大气层
and preserves our air.
即使有磁场保护
But even with a magnetic field
地表仍充满炎热和混乱
violence and chaos continued to plague our planet.
由于炎热的铁核
Above the Earth's iron core,
外层的岩石被融化
its rocky mantle was melting
形成突出地表的火山
forming volcanoes that rose to the surface
不断释放有毒气体和火山灰
and burped up noxious gases and lava.
同时小行星撞击依然不断发生着
And the collisions kept coming.
地球形成史上一次重要撞击改变了这一切
One impact would forever change the course of Earth's history
人类的宿命
and the fate of mankind.
地球诞生5千万年后的某时
About 50 million years after the Earth began forming
一个巨大的撞击改变了地球发展方向
it experienced a collision that would steer it in a new direction.
一个火星大小的星体撞击地球
An object the size of Mars
拥有当时地球体积80%大小
slammed right into Earth, which was already 80% of its total size.
巨大爆炸融化了两个星球的外表
The explosive impact melted both the planets' outer layers
融合并形成了一个更大的地球
and fused the two together to form a larger Earth.
一些散落的其他碎片结合在一起形成了月球
Some molten debris that didn't blend together coalesced to shape our Moon.
星体研究专家比尔首先发表了这样的理论
Planetary scientist Bill Hartmann, first proposed this theory
在美国国家航空航天局(NASA)的第一次登月任务之后
after NASA's first mission to the Moon.
阿波罗宇航员带回来一些岩石
When the Apollo astronauts brought back rocks from the Moon
可以了解这些岩石的产生
and we could actually see what the rocks were made of,
最后发现
they found out that…
这些岩石非常像地球上发现的火山岩
the rocks are like lava that you can find on Earth.
这表明地球和月球的构成非常相似
Which tells you that the Moon material and the Earth material are very similar.
与地球关系密切的月球
Earth's intimate relationship with its moon
给地球成长带来诸多好处
gave the growing planet a competitive edge.
月球的存在导致
The Moon is what causes the seasons because
在一年的某些时候北极朝着太阳
some parts of the earthen North Pole is tilted toward the Sun
另一些时间 南极朝着太阳
and later on the South Pole is tilted toward the Sun.
月球一直保持着一个倾角 在万有引力作用下
The Moon holds that tilt steady. The various gravity forces that are exerted
始终保持在一个固定倾角
tend to act in a way that holds that steady.
在这次创造了月球的伟大的碰撞中
After the epic collision which created our moon,
地球获得了超过90%的物质
our planet was over 90% of its total mass.
这个地球形成过程
The planetary formation process
使地球具有生物进化的基础
involves almost a biological competition
来自于这些高速撞击获得的物质
of many bodies bashing into each other at very high speeds.
当39亿年前碰撞停止时
When the collisions subsided nearly 3,9 billion years ago,
太阳系形成了8大行星
our solar system was left with eight planets.
包括冥王星则有9大行星
Or nine if you still count Pluto.
地球处在了绕日运行的第三个位置
Earth secured the third orbital position from the Sun,
离太阳930万英里
which is now 93 million miles away.
几大行星各不相同
Planets don't like each other,
取决于各自的引力
because they're gravitationally tugging each other.
排列着
So they're equally spaced.
每个行星都一个一个隔着一定的距离
Each planet is a certain fraction further from the Sun.
这些是太阳系中的流浪者
The objects that didn't become planets became refugees.
这些小行星大多由石块和铁构成
Asteroids, made of rock and iron,
存在于火星与木星的轨道之间
found asylum in the Asteroid Belt between Mars and Jupiter.
彗星由冰 尘土和石块构成
Comets, composed of ices dust and rock,
一些存在于太阳系的古比皮带
sought shelter in the Kuiper Belt,
位于海王星轨道外层
just beyond the planet Neptune.
另一些聚集成奥尔特云远离地球10亿英里以外的地方
Others migrated to the Oort Cloud, over a trillion miles from Earth.
非常相似于这些撞坏的保时捷
This battered Porsches are a good analogue
包含着大量小行星和彗星的早期太阳系
to the early Solar System, the comets and asteroids
这些小星体从诞生之初幸存下来
that survived the early days.
同这些车一样保存着其所有部件
And like these cars, which are kept here for their parts,
我们依然可以去寻找这些重要部件
we can also ** comets and asteroids for vital parts
这些太阳系诞生之初就形成的小星体
that have been stored since the formation of the Solar System.
在地球形成历史中
Over the course of Earth's history,
一些小行星可能改变了自己的运行轨道
many misguided asteroids have strayed off their orbital path
落到地球上 成为地球的一部分
and landed on our planet as meteorites.
近年来 科学家们分析了这些外来物
Over the years, scientists have analysed these meteorites
通过放射性同位素衰减测其年龄
and determined their age through radioactive dating.
由于它们与地球同时期诞生
And since meteorites were formed at the same time as our planets,
这也得出地球的年龄
they provide the age of Earth.
大约45亿年
Roughly 4.5 billion years old.
科学家的这种特别思路
Scientifically this is fantastic.
就像寻找你的家族历史
It's like looking at your family history
想办法找出最初的家传物品
and finding pieces of your first relative all the way
追溯他们的历史
back in Earth's history.
虽然在外漂流很久
They're still out there.
小行星和彗星们
Asteroids and comets
同时可能又是我们
may also shed light
地球上水的来源
on the origins of water on our planet.
39亿年前
3.9 billion years ago,
地球开始冷却 形成坚硬的硅酸盐外壳
the Earth cooled, forming a thick silicate crust over its mantle,
覆盖在铁镍内核之外
an iron and nickel core.
很快地温暖的地面覆盖了大量的水
Warm liquid soon covered the planet's surface,
除了点缀在地球上的一些火山岛
except for a few volcanic islands dotting the globe.
地球的又一个特别幸运之处
One of the Earth's lucky properties
是诞生在一个恰当的地方
is that it happened to be born in just the right place,
这是一个适合生存的区域
in what's called the habitable zone.
跟太阳保持足够的距离
It's the right distance from the Sun,
海洋不会被蒸发
where its ocean does not boil away,
因为不是太热
but not too hot.
同样又离太阳不是太远海洋也不至于被冰冻
Or too far away, where its ocean freezes over.
但是地表的这么多水来自何方？
But where did Earth get all this water?
一种假说认为是来自于火山爆发
One view is that water came from volcanoes,
这些早期地球上所存在的大量火山
which have been around since the early formation of Earth.
向大气中喷发了大量水蒸气
Volcanoes spewed out massive amounts of steam into the atmosphere.
在地球降温的过程中结成雨水
When the Earth cooled, volcanic steam condensed into rain
于是向地面注入了大量的水
and thereby supplied the planet with water.
但是火山的水源来自何方？
But where did the steamy water emitted from volcanoes come from?
火山运动循环着许多物质
Volcanoes basically recycle material from melted rock
地表的任何覆盖物
in the mantle of the Earth.
包括水
Including water.
当然这不是凭空创造的水来自于早期海洋
But that's not really new water in the sense that it was there before in the oceans
已经循环了许多次了
and is coming out again for a second time.
美国国家航空航天局(NASA) 科学家 迈克尔·穆马
NASA's senior scientist, Michael Mumma,
认为地球上的水
says our planet's water
来自太空
came from space.
一些由冰组成的彗星
Comets, which are made up of frozen gases,
给地球来了一场淋浴
could have showered Earth with water
在地球形成之初就不断发生着
during the relentless impacts of its infancy.
这些小冰体提供的水量
The deliver of water from an icy body
取决于他们的大小
depends very critically on how large the particle is.
较小的个体在大气层外部就蒸发了
The smaller bodies that came in would break up high in the atmosphere.
其他的才能把他们的物质留在地表
The other bodies delivered their material to the surface of the Earth,
他们自身蒸发后
and they can actually vaporize that material
成为地球上的水
that becomes the water on Earth.
穆马试图证实水是否是来自彗星
Mumma is trying to determine if cometary water
彗星的水组成成分应该跟地球一样
is made up of the same ingredients as our planet's water.
我们知道海洋中拥有地球上水的混合物
We know the Earth's oceans contain a mixture of normal water,
水(氧化氢)
H2O,
与重水(氧化氘)
and heavy water, HDO,
含有氘
which includes deuterium,
一种氢的同位素 为氢质量的两倍
a form of hydrogen that is twice as heavy as normal hydrogen.
但是研究彗星十分困难
But comets are difficult to study.
它们极少靠近地球
Few pass near our planet
绝大部分都在太阳系外部
because most orbit in the outer solar system.
不过在1986年 欧洲空间局发射的探测器乔托号近距离地访问了一个彗星
But in 1986, Europe's Giotto spacecraft had a close encounter with Comet Halley,
著名的哈雷彗星
also known as Halley's Comet,
距离地球3800万英里
which was 38 million miles from Earth.
一个分析样本的方法
One of the ways we analyze samples
使用光谱分析仪
is to fly mass spectrometers
分析透过彗星的光谱结构
through cometary debris that's coming off the comet when it's active.
用这种方法精确地测量气体
And we can measure the gases very accurately in this way.
来自于哈雷彗星
This was done for Comet Halley.
哈雷彗星的水相似于地球
Comet Halley's water is similar to that on Earth.
但是目前分析的其他彗星的水
However, the other comets analyzed so far,
重水比例是地球水的两倍
have twice the amount of HDO, or heavy water, that's in our oceans.
我们也开始观察彗星的其他化合物
We know now, by looking at other compounds in comets,
并不都相同
that they're not all the same.
因此我们不知道哈雷彗星是否
So we don't know whether Comet Halley
是最有代表的彗星
was in fact representative of all comets.
我们目前研究的彗星
Most comets studied thus far
多处于古比皮带位于太阳系外部
have come from the Kuiper Belt, located in the outer solar system.
这些彗星也许跟地球形成没有联系
So, they probably didn't help form planet Earth.
但是通过在夏威夷的大型双子望远镜
But the Gemini North Telescope, in Hawaii,
最近发现了某些彗星存在于一个不寻常之处
recently discovered comets in an unlikely place.
这就是火星和木星间的小行星带
The Asteroid Belt located between Mars and Jupiter.
这些相对温暖的彗星也许拥有着与地球一样的水
These warmer ice-bearing bodies may have the same water as Earth,
它们在太阳系内部运转更靠近太阳
because they were all formed in the inner solar system, which is closer to the Sun.
令人惊异的更多证据表明
What's more, startling new evidence suggests
这些不寻常的彗星不但可能给地球带来了水
that these unusual comets may not only have delivered water to Earth,
甚至在地球上播种
they also may have seeded our planet
带来那些基本生命单元
with the building blocks of life.
生命的起源
The origin of life.
始终是地球的一个迷
It remains one of the most puzzling and controversial questions about our Planet.
可以确定的是在39亿年前
One thing is certain: 3.9 billion years ago,
相比之下人类历史只是非常短的一段时间
humans would have lasted for only a brief moment.
大气含有大量二氧化碳 水蒸气
The Earth's atmosphere consisted of carbon dioxide, water vapour,
以及少量氮气 却没有氧
a little nitrogen, but no oxygen.
但是原始生命如何才能在这样环境下生存？
Yet, could primitive life have endured in such an environment?
我们没有确切的证明约43亿年前的环境能产生生命
We have no firm evidence that there was life 4.3 billion years ago,
现在我们相信这些都是可能的
but we think now that the conditions were possible.
一些地球上最古老的化石
The oldest fossils on Earth
形成于大约37到39亿年前
only date back 3.7 to 3.9 billion years ago.
一些人认为这些最原始的生命
Some believe that these remains once evolved
在那些古老的湖泊中进化出来的
in ancient ponds or lakes.
这里大气中的化合物在能量作用下
There, atmospheric chemicals and energy
形成了含有一些基本氨基酸的汤
formed a primordial soup of amino acids,
生命的基本材料
the essential elements of life.
但是万一这些原始生命
But, could the building blocks of life
来自于别处？
have come from somewhere else?
也许是天外来物？
Perhaps from an extraterrestrial object?
包括各种氨基酸的有机物
Meteorites contain organic materials, including amino acids.
因某些原因形成于太阳系某处
They were formed somehow in the earlier solar system.
然后这些有机物从太空中来到地球
So there is this delivery of organic material from space.
但是如果小行星和彗星
But, if asteroids and comets
携带基本生命物质
gave the building blocks of life
空间旅行 来到地球
a space shuttle ride to Earth,
如何在高速撞击中存活
how did they survive the high velocity impact?
回到美国国家航空航天局(NASA)--埃姆斯研究中心
Back at NASA's Ames research facility,
皮特·舒尔茨 和 小泽杉田正进行着一项
Pete Schultz and Seiji Sugita are conducting another
先进的实验依然使用VGR(垂直射击靶场)
cutting-edge experiment using the VGR.
他们希望用1天的时间确认那些流行和彗星
They hope to one day confirm that meteorites and comets
能够把基本生命物质带到地球上来
could have delivered life's essential ingredients to Earth.
其中一点 我们观测其如何生存
One of the things we are trying to look at, what is the survival*
这些来到地球的物质
of some of these building blocks? Can they be delivered to the earth
播种地球
so they would help seed a planet
创造了生命起源的条件
so the conditions for life could begin to exist?
彗星和小行星可能带来
Comets and asteroids probably brought
原始生命的基本物质
essential ingredients for origin of life
来到地球表面
to the surface of the Earth.
撞击创造的环境
Their impact probably made the surface environment
更有利于生命
much more favourable for life.
他们的实验显示这些流星
Their experiments show that meteorites
给早期地球带来了这些基本的碳化合物
delivered primitive carbon compounds to early Earth.
其中一些
Some of these compounds may have produced
是生命形成的基本元素
the building blocks necessary for life.
但是还需要更多的研究
But more research is needed.
这些穿过大气时产生了燃烧
So this is coming through the atmosphere, burning up as we go.
目前多数科学家一致认为生命的最初形式
Still, many scientists agree the first life forms
单细胞生命体都诞生于早期海洋中
were single-cell organisms that lived in the oceans.
今天 生物学家们找到了
And today, biologists are digging up
我们这些最初的祖先的后代
the descendants of our earliest known ancestors
存在于地球上一些最不适宜生存的地方
in some of the most uninhabitable places on Earth.
把一辆凯迪拉克比作现代生命
If you have a big Cadillac today as modern life,
远古生命就像一辆自行车
ancient life was more like a bicycle.
除了一些化合物 它们没有留下其他任何遗迹
There are no remains of these organisms other than their chemistry,
在我看来非常重要的是
and I think it's important to keep in mind
地球生命的最初20亿年
that for the first 2 billion years of this planet's living history,
都是微生物时期
it was all microbial.
肯恩·尼尔森 教授是一个微生物收集者
Professor Ken Nealson is a bona fide microbe hunter.
在世界各处寻找那些最小的
He scours the planet for the tiniest forms of primitive life
依然存在的低等生物
that still exist today.
最初地球上充满了氢 硫化氢
The earliest Earth was full of hydrogen, of hydrogen sulphate,
甲烷以及一些二氧化碳
had a lot of methane, some carbon dioxide.
这是一个充满能量的地方
It was a place full of energy.
微生物充斥着
The microbes exploited virtually
地球的几乎每个角落
every niche on this planet for energy.
有人称这些低等生物为
Some have dubbed these early life forms
嗜温生物或嗜极生物
extremophiles or thermophiles,
就是能在极端环境下生存的微生物
organisms that can live in extreme environments.
想象一下有大量流行撞击地球
Let's say there was a massive meteorite that hit the Earth
温度升到40多度
and the temperature of the Earth went up 40 degrees.
很好 很适合这些嗜温生物
Well, that would be just perfect for these extremophiles.
如我们所知 像这些生物
One of the things we know, for instance, is that
非常相似于远古的那些生物
the"oldest" organisms, the ones that are nearest to the last common ancestor,
都是这样的嗜温生物
are all thermophilic organisms.
你可能要问 生命如何在如此的高温下进化？
And you could say, well that proves that life evolved at high temperature.
如今这些生物的后代 能适应更高的温度
Descendents of these hot-blooded organisms can be found today
能够生存在华氏230度的高温中
and they can live at temperatures of 230 ℃.
如果你想见识这些所谓嗜温生物 来黄石国家公园
If you want some so called thermophiles, then you go to Yellowstone
你会发现这些沸腾的湖 像煮沸的开水锅
and you see these bubbling lakes and cauldrons of smelly water.
亿万年来 这里看起来依然是不毛之地
And for years people assumed they were sterile,
其实却充满着生命
but they're full of life.
所有适合生存于此的生命体
And only these organisms* adapting to that extreme.
这些现代嗜温生物表明
Modern day extremophiles may prove
生命的能够生存和适应
that life could have survived and adapted
如地球早期的那些极端环境之下
under the extreme conditions on Earth during its turbulent infancy.
只是这些单细胞生物如何进化成复杂高等生物
But, how could single-celled microbes transform into complex life?
大约在30亿年前
Approximately 3 billion years ago,
原始生物靠吸收太阳能生存
primitive life soaked up energy from the Sun.
这些水中微生物具有叶绿素
Underwater microbes formed a green pigment called chlorophyll.
能够吸收太阳光
This enabled them to trap sunlight
并通过一些化学反应
and produce a chemical reaction
把二氧化碳和水变成养料
which converts carbon dioxide and water into food.
这个过程--光合作用过程使得这些细菌聚集起来
This process, called photosynthesis, led the way for bacteria to multiply
形成地球上的最初的多细胞结构 藻青菌
into one of Earth's earlier structures: cyanobacteria,
就是所知的"蓝藻"
formerly called"blue-green algae".
蓝藻开始从水中大量释放氧气
Cyanobacteria injected vast amounts of free oxygen into the water and air
爆发了一场氧气革命
and sparked the oxygen revolution.
不久生命开始分两个方向进化
All of a sudden, life divided into two groups.
一部分是无需氧气的厌氧生物
One that ran away from the oxygen and hid in the anaerobic part of the world,
其他的则使用氧气
and the other that started using the oxygen
用来燃烧消耗能量
as a great energetic advantage,
然后它们能够进化的更大
and then could evolve, I think, to be much bigger,
以及进化的更快
and perhaps to evolve much faster.
相信这些蓝藻需要更大的身体
One thing is for sure, when the cyanobacteria got this ability,
与其他个体竞争
they outcompeted everybody else.
得益于这些菌类 生命快速地多样化起来
Thanks to cyanobacteria, life was able to quickly diversify
变得越来越复杂
and become more complex.
没有他们就没有氧分子的大量存在
Without it, molecular oxygen wouldn't exist.
也将不会进化出任何动植物和人类
Therefore, plants, animals and humans would have never developed.
没有它们 怎能有今天的我们？
So if we didn't have the cyanobacteria we wouldn't be around.
我们是这些地球微生物的后代
We owe our heritage to the scum of the Earth.
都从同一个地方进化而来
All of us came from the same place.
我们都有许多共同点 跟这些微生物一样
We have so many things in common with bacteria
这些是毋庸置疑的
that there's just no doubt about it.
莫哈韦沙漠死亡之地
The Mojave Desert, near Death Valley
位于南加利福尼亚看起来没有生命
in Southern California, appears void of life.
但在这些干涸的湖床之下
But below the surface of this dry lake bed,
人类的最初远祖繁衍着
mankind's ancestors thrive.
地球上那些最初的生命
Planet Earth's earliest life forms
能够适应如此极端的环境
may have adapted and persevered under extreme conditions.
如今 在干旱荒芜的南加州莫哈韦沙漠
Today, in the parched and barren Mojave Desert, in Southern California,
地理生物学家肯恩·尼尔森整探寻着生命的秘密
geobiologist Ken Nealson is searching for the secrets to life.
发现现代微生物们
He's discovered that modern microbial organisms
依然繁衍在这样的不毛之地
also thrive in some inhospitable places.
观察这里你能发现什么？
What you see when you glance at this environment are
看起来是很多这样的沟壑与土堆
a bunch of what appear to be tunnels or mounds here,
却是由生活着的微生物排出的大量气体所造成
and these are made by the gases produced by the microbes living
而这原本是平整的土地
in this mudflat area.
如果你带了水 并淋湿这块土壤
If we were to take water and rehydrate this piece of dirt
把它放到显微镜之下
and put this under the microscope,
会发现水里飘满了微生物
it would be rife with abundant microbes swimming everywhere.
就是繁衍在这些贫瘠土地之中的生命
And this is the lifecycle on the saltflat,
我们所称的这些嗜极生物
all of which we call extremophiles,
很好的生存于这样的荒原上
and which eke out an existence in a mudflat like this.
微生物统治着整个地球
Microbes reigned supreme for much of Earth's history.
改变着整个世界
They revolutionized the planet
为高等物种的出现创造了条件
and paved the way for a myriad of sophisticated species.
不过直到陆地的大块出现才给了生物们一个新家
But it was land that gave life a new home.
也就是陆地上升时期
It's believed the emergence of landmass began roughly
大约始于40亿年前
4 billion years ago.
地壳板块运动的不断加热和挤压
Plate tectonics created heat and pressure,
从海平面上升起大量岩石 陆地
that produced rock lighter than the ocean floor.
随后不断的飘浮与结合
It ultimately floated and accumulated
形成了大块的陆地 并不断地改变的形状
creating continents that would change in size and shape over time.
地球大陆的出现
The presence of vast continents would enable Earth
承载着这独特的一切
to sustain its most distinctive component,
复杂高等生物
complex life.
经过超过20亿年的不断进化
After 2 billion years of planetary and biological evolution,
最初的两栖射生物开始爬上陆地
the first plants and animals emerged from water onto land.
但是数亿年后
But it would take hundreds of millions of years
人类出现
before humans evolved.
自从人类统治这里
And once Man claimed dominance over the planet,
地球永远将是独一无二的
Earth would never be the same.
地球是人类最佳栖息处
Planet Earth now holds the best real estate
在太阳系中
for mankind in our solar system.
7大洲和无数岛屿
Seven diverse continents and countless islands
是60亿人口的家园
are home to 6 billion people.
非常难以置信地生存于地球上多数时期的
Yet, remarkably, most of Earth's existence thus far,
并不是人类
has been without humans.
将整个地球历史比作一个24小时的钟
The planet's history has been compared to a 24-hour clock,
人类的出现只是1天的最后2秒钟
with the presence of Man being the last 2 seconds of the day.
我们现在围绕跑到缓慢驾驶
We're driving around the track now at a relatively modest speed
这样行驶平稳易于掌控
in this car that handles very smoothly. A very controlled ride.
对我来说就像地球上的生命
This reminds me of life on Earth.
盛衰变换着
Life on Earth has had its ups and downs,
相比较于其他行星的发展
but compared to evolution of other planets
数亿年时间里都非常相似
the Earth has had a relatively smooth ride for billions of years.
这就是生命繁衍于此的原因
That's why life has flourished here.
现在随着人类对未来的改变
But with mankind now navigating its future,
地球这艘太空船开始发生剧烈变化
Spaceship Earth may return to its tumultuous beginnings.
人类使用各种手段
Humans, through trial-and-error evolution,
使得地球适合人类居住 成为一个特别的星球
are suited to live on this particular planet.
就像现在这样 而不管将来如何
Now, that's true right now. We don't know if that will be true in the future.
同样地 人类创造了大量难以置信的东西
Earthlings created what once would seem almost unimaginable.
科技
Technology.
车辆 机械和电子仪器
Mechanical vehicles, gadgets and gizmos
简化并改进着我们的生活
have simplified and bettered our lives.
大多数制品所依赖的于化学材料 燃料
Many of these conveniences are run on or made using fossil fuels,
都是从地壳中获得
which are harvested from the Earth's crust.
但是最近100年来
But over the last hundred years,
我们的改变引起了一些全球化的问题
our innovations have gotten us into planetary trouble.
人类对地球的影响越来越大
Humans are having a major effect on Planet Earth,
像全球变暖和人口爆炸问题
with global warming, and population explosion,
给环境造成巨大影响
so we're having a very large effect on the environment.
温室效应
The natural greenhouse effect
是指大气吸收红外辐射
is the absorption of infrared radiation
保持地球温暖
by our atmosphere, which warms our planet.
没有温室气体地球表面会比现在低86华氏度
Without greenhouse gases, the Earth's surface would be up to 86 ℉ cooler.
但是最近20年温室气体增长过快
But in the last 20 years there's been an increase in greenhouse gases,
特别是二氧化碳
especially carbon dioxide
产生于化学燃料燃烧
produced by burning fossil fuels.
温度的上升直接影响到农业
The increased heating is affecting agriculture,
海平面和气候
sea level and weather.
过去二氧化碳含量也曾提升
In the past, carbon dioxide levels had spiked
是自然火山生成的
due to natural causes, such as volcanic outgassing.
然而增长比想象的要快
However, today's rises seem to be happening much more rapidly.
为了观察温室效应带来的巨大的变化
To visibly witness the drastic changes
我们来到不适宜人类居住的地方
one needs to travel to the barely habitable zones on Planet Earth.
这个长的像人类的冰山将
There, mankind's future
逐渐融化消失
is literally melting away.
地球的南北极众所周知的
The Earth's North and South Poles are known as the cryospheres,
拥有大量冰雪
regions blanketed with snow and ice.
调节着地球气温与水平面
They help regulate climate temperature and water levels around the globe.
美国国家航空航天局(NASA)科学家-瓦里得·阿布德拉底
NASA Senior Scientist, Waleed Abdalati,
调查世界上的冰冻区
investigates the frozen parts of our world.
站在冰上感觉很奇妙
The feeling of being on the ice is amazing.
非常荣幸的能够踏上这些地方 这就是我第一次站在冰面上的感受
It's pristine…in places where probably my boots have been to touch the ground there.
会觉得自己很渺小
It's very humbling…
站在那儿你感受到一种巨大 非常难忘
You stand there and it's so vast and impressive…
但是最近一个世纪以来
But in the last century,
科学家们比如阿布德拉底博士
scientists like Dr. Abdalati
证实了冰层的消失
have personally witnessed Earth's ice shrinking.
原因是白色的冰雪
The reason: ice and snow are white,
反射阳光冷却地球
they reflect sunlight and cool the planet.
相反的海洋吸收阳光
By contrast, the open oceans absorb sunlight,
温暖地球
which heats the globe.
然而融化的冰产生了更多水
However, as ice melts, it creates more open water
吸收了更多阳光使地球更温暖
which sucks in more sunlight and increasingly warms the planet
然后又融化更多的冰
and melts more ice.
我们说这是不稳定状态
It's unstable, we say,
即使一个小的改变
because even the slightest change
也会带来巨大变化
tends to amplify itself.
很典型的恶性循环
And it's essentially a runaway effect.
地极现在很危险
Earth's polar ice caps are in peril.
这些持续融化的宝贵风景
Continually melting of these precious landscapes
也许会在某个时刻带来灾难
may one day produce catastrophes across the planet.
在南极
At the South Pole, the continent of Antarctica,
那儿拥有世界70%的淡水
holds 70% of the world's fresh water.
这些大陆边缘的冰保护着内部的冰 就像胡佛大坝那样
Ice shelves surrounding the continent hold back ice like the Hoover Dam.
但是现在很脆弱
But they are weakening.
已经存在了超过12000年的
After 12.000 years of solidity
拉森 B冰层仅仅在5周时间就坍塌消失了
the Larsen B Ice Shelf collapsed in just 5 weeks.
在北极
At the North Pole,
有人预言 北冰洋夏天将不再结冰
some predict that the Arctic Ocean will be ice-free during the summer
也许仅仅只是40-60年之后
in the next 40 to 60 years.
这样的高温到底是如果产生的？
What's causing the warm temperatures
一部分是自然 自身的变化原因
certainly there's an element of natural variability,
但是人的作用更不可忽视
but there is also a human contribution.
我们知道人类促使全球气温上升
We know that humans are contributing to the warmer environment
这加速了冰层的消失
and that we're subsequently contributing to diminish ice cover.
在格陵兰岛雅各布港冰川
In Greenland, the Jakobshavn Glacier,
世界上流动最快的冰川
one of the fastest flowing glaciers in the world,
就像运行着的一列火车
is now moving like a runaway train.
现在它快速运动着
So it's now going about
每小时5英尺
5 ft/hour, which believe me, for a glacier is very fast.
最糟糕的情况就是所有冰川
The worst-case scenario would be that all of these glaciers
越来越来地流失 大量的冰流入海中
start to speed up and just deliver huge amounts of ice to the sea.
这将提升海平面差不多3英尺
That would be a 3-foot increase worldwide.
在海岸临近区域 3英尺意味着
And 3 feet in coastal regions
冲击至少千万计的人类
is plenty to displace millions and millions of people.
虽然人类可以迁移到稳定地区
Although humans may be able to stabilize
但是人类制造的垃圾 最多几十年
man-made pollutants, it might take decades.
这时自然界的破坏就将起作用
At the same time, there are natural processes at work
决定人类的命运
that might determine mankind's fate.
地球会一直进行自身的发展进化
The planet's going through its own evolution.
我们对地球的所做只会影响我们自己 而非地球
What we do to the planet affects us, it doesn't affect the planet.
我们可以建一个大气的模型
So we may mock up with the atmosphere
上千年的全球变暖之类
for a few thousand years of global warming and so forth,
事实上这只对人类而言很重要
but this is actually just a blip. It's an important blip to us,
对于行星自身发展不重要
but it's not necessarily a blip in terms of planetary evolution.
唐纳德·布朗利 和 彼得·沃德
Donald Brownlee and colleague Peter Ward
测量了一些地球上生命赖以生存的信号
have measured our planet's vital signs,
预计结果令人担忧
and its prognosis it's bleak.
地球作为动物和人类的生存之地
Earth, as a place for animal and human life,
开始进入老年时期
is nearing old age.
为什么？
Why?
太阳将越来越亮 越热
Our Sun is getting brighter and hotter.
地球上高等生物面临的问题
The problem down the line for advanced life on Earth
是因为太阳变得更亮了些
is that as the Sun gets slightly brighter,
假设
the expectation is
完全去除大气中的全部二氧化碳
that carbon dioxide will be almost completely removed from the atmosphere.
这会导致地球动植物的灭亡
There will be an end to the age of plants and animals.
人类也将在500万年内灭亡
Humans could die out 500 million years from now
因为越来越热的太阳
due to the brightening of the Sun.
但是 在一些完美计划下
But in the grand scheme of things
人类或许能顺利发展
Man may have had a good run.
躲过灭亡的命运
Before reaching extinction,
人类将可以生存在更复杂的环境下
perhaps humans will have lived longer than any other complex species
通过自身努力改变自然环境
because of their ability to adapt to changing environmental conditions.
从人类视角来看
From a human standpoint,
保时捷中的地球司机像其它行星将继续行驶
the Earth will remain been a Porsche planet probably for another…
5或10亿年时间
half a billion to a billion years.
这个时间单位
Which is a truly awesome timescale
对于人类实在太长了
from a human standpoint.
通过利用地球上来历不明的水
As Spaceship Earth manoeuvres through uncharted waters,
人类思考着地球诞生的奇异之处
humankind can reflect on the planet's awesome achievements
地球自身又坚毅地生存于
and steadfast survival
荒凉的邻空
in the tough neighbourhood
这就是宇宙
called THE UNIVERSE.
谢谢观赏
Thanks For Viewing